<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>InterMine Training Portal</title>
    <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/</link>
    <description>Recent content on InterMine Training Portal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 0</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video00/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video00/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to InterMine python tutorial! In this tutorial, I will show you how to interact with the intermine registry, which lists the different InterMines available on the web, and contains information about their URLs, the datasets and organisms you can find in each InterMine, and a few other things.
First, don’t forget to run pip install intermine in your terminal, if you haven’t already.
Then, let’s look at cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 0: Overview</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/00/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/00/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial is for users who use Python to get information of a mine or an organism. This tutorial consists of 14 parts.
We use Flymine as an example.
  We recommend you to use Jupyter Notebook to run following code. If you are new to Jupyter, you can visit this
Text Tutorial   Video Tutorial     You can see the script here 
 Try Live  You can try live here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 1</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video01/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the first intermine python tutorial! In this tutorial, we will go through the basics of intermine python queries and how to write your first query. To get started, you would want to ‘pip install intermine’ in your terminal first.
Let’s look at cells. We start by importing the service class from InterMine’s webservice module. Let’s click it.
Then let’s create a query object. The “new query” method can help us do this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 1: The Basics of a Query</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/01/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will tell you about the basics of intermine-python queries and how to write your first query. Text Tutorial   Video Tutorial     You can see the script here
Try Live  You can try live here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 2</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video02/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the second tutorial in the InterMine python tutorial series! In the previous tutorial we learned how to select the output columns of choice. In this tutorial, we’ll look at adding constraints to our queries to filter the results.
Let’s start with creating a service and query object, like we saw earlier.
If we want to view all the possible output columns at once, we can pass “*” as a parameter to the select function like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 2: Adding Constraints to a Query</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/02/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial, we will look at adding constraints to our queries to filter the results. Text Tutorial   Video Tutorial     You can see the script here
Try Live  You can try live here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 3</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video03/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the third tutorial in the InterMine python tutorial series! In the previous tutorial, we learned about adding constraints to our query so that we could filter the results. In this tutorial we will take a look at some more different types of constraints.
First, let’s create a query object like we saw earlier.
The first type of constraint we will look at is Unary Constraint. A unary constraint is one that does not take any value but can be used to check if a particular attribute is absent or present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 3: More about Constraints</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/03/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial we will take a look at some more constraints and the different types of constraints. Text Tutorial   Video Tutorial     You can see the script here
Try Live  You can try live here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 4</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video04/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the fourth tutorial in the InterMine python tutorial series! In the previous tutorials we learned about the basic backbone of a query - views and constraints. This short tutorial will talk about another feature of an InterMine query - Outer and Inner Joins.
When we add a path to a query, even if it is in the view, then by default there is a constraint involved. Our query will consist of only those records that have information in the fields or attributes that are described by the path.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 4: Query Features</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/04/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial we will talk about another feature of an intermine query - Outer and Inner Joins. Text Tutorial   Video Tutorial     You can see the script here
Try Live  You can try live here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 5</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video05/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the fifth tutorial in the InterMine python tutorial series! This tutorial will talk about dealing with the results of our query. You can either store the results into a file (using a library like csv) or you can process the results immediately after you extract them.
Now we write a short query for genes, and add all views for publications associated with that gene, then explore the results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 5: Query Results</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/05/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial we will talk about dealing with the results of our query. Text Tutorial   Video Tutorial     You can see the script here
Try Live  You can try live here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 6</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video06/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the sixth tutorial in the InterMine python tutorial series! In the previous tutorials we learned how to add filters to limit the query results. However, it is often useful to view the results without filters. This tutorial will show you how to process, sort, and analyse the query results.
Usually, we begin by creating a query object. Our example for this tutorial is going to be related to gene expression, represented in InterMine by the RNA Sequence Result class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 6: Advanced Results Management</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/06/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will show you how to process, sort, and analyse the query results. Text Tutorial   Video Tutorial     You can see the script here
Try Live  You can try live here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 7</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video07/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial we will look at templates, which are like pre-prepared queries you can easily re-use. Templates can do everything that a query can do. Everything that you can do with a query - add new constraints, add new views, process the results using the results iterator can be done with templates as well.
While writing queries of your own, you would have probably realized that there is a lot of duplication of effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 7: Templates</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/07/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial we will look at templates, which are like pre-prepared queries you can easily re-use. Text Tutorial   Video Tutorial     You can see the script here
Try Live  You can try live here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 8</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video08/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the eighth tutorial in the InterMine python tutorial series! This very short tutorial will talk about how to access your saved templates and lists if you have your login information (username and password). If you don’t have an account, you can create one at flymine.org
Once you have made an account, you can use the web service to create a query of your choice and save it as a template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 8: Accessing Templates</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/08/</guid>
      <description> This tutorial will talk about how to access your saved templates and lists if you have your login information (username and password). Text Tutorial   Video Tutorial     You can see the script here
Try Live   You can try live here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 9</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video09/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the ninth tutorial in the InterMine python tutorial series! This tutorial will talk about how you can create and save lists in your account. You will need to provide your login information while creating a service object like in the previous tutorial.
You can either provide a list of identifiers (for example, gene symbols) and the InterMine Server will try to match them with objects in the database, or you can provide a query that specifies exactly what you want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 9: Lists</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/09/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will talk about how you can create and save lists in your account. Text Tutorial   Video Tutorial     You can see the script here
Try Live  You can try live here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 10</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video10/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the tenth tutorial in the InterMine python tutorial series! This tutorial will talk about how you can perform enrichment calculations on lists that you have access to.
‘Enrichment’ means that the feature (GO term, domain) occurs for those genes more than would be expected by chance. It is calculated using the hypergeometric distribution which is described further in the InterMine documentation
Enrichment widgets are useful to find items such as GO Terms or publications which are associated with your gene list more than would be expected by chance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 10: Enrichment Calculations</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/10/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will talk about how you can perform enrichment calculations on lists that you have access to. Text Tutorial   Video Tutorial     You can see the script here
Try Live  You can try live here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 11</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video11/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the eleventh tutorial in the InterMine python tutorial series! This tutorial will talk about how you can combine two lists easily in InterMine.
Like previous tutorials, this tutorial will require you to login into your InterMine account so that the lists that you will combine can be saved.
To make things easier, I use a test account here. Don’t forget to enter your username and password, execute it and then proceed with the rest of the tutorial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 11: Combining Lists</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/11/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will talk about how you can combine two lists and save results in your account easily in InterMine. Text Tutorial   Video Tutorial     You can see the script here
Try Live  You can try live here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 12</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video12/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the twelfth tutorial in the InterMine python tutorial series! This tutorial will cover some more functionalities of a query. Queries are the basis of all research in InterMine. Being able to manage them more effectively is always useful.
First, we create a query object like we saw earlier, and select the gene symbol and organism as the views.
Let’s say that the query is not as simple as a strict cumulative filter and the user wants combinations of constraints.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 12: More about Queries</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/12/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will cover some more functionalities of a query. Queries are the basis of all research in InterMine and being able to manage them more effectively is always useful. Text Tutorial   Video Tutorial     You can see the script here
Try Live  You can try live here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 13</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video13/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the thirteenth tutorial in the InterMine python tutorial series! This tutorial will tell you about the Query Manager and how you can take advantage of it to make better use of queries. We hope at this stage you have the &amp;lsquo;intermine&amp;rsquo; package installed.
We start by importing the module from the InterMine package.
The next step will be to access the account we want to manage: save_mine_and_token is a method to access an account from a particular mine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 13: Query Manager</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/13/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will tell you about the Query Manager especially functions of it and how you can take advantage of Query Manager to make better use of queries. Text Tutorial   Video Tutorial     You can see the script here
Try Live  You can try live here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 14</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video14/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the fourteenth tutorial in the InterMine python tutorial series! With the great need for data visualisation in the present world, we have introduced a few visual features to InterMine as well. This tutorial will have details of how we can visualise the data using the Python client.
This feature of the Python Client is supported only on Python versions &amp;gt;= 3.6 because of the dependencies. So please update your Python environment if needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 14: Visualisation in InterMine</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/14/</guid>
      <description>With the great need for data visualisation in the present world, we have introduced a few visual features to Intermine as well. We have tried to cover the most common needs of visualisation and have explained their use in this tutorial. Text Tutorial   Video Tutorial     You can see the script here
Try Live  You can try live here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 15</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-scripts/video15/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the fifteenth tutorial in the InterMine python tutorial series! This tutorial will help you utilise the module to get details about the data model of various mines. These are additional examples, besides the ones covered here - http://intermine.org/intermine-ws-python/intermine.html#module-intermine.model. Each class (data type) has information containing references to other objects in the data model, collections of references or attribute details.
Let&#39;s begin by showing all the fields a data type contains (including all Attributes, References and Collections listed alphabetically).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 15: Simple Ways to Manipulate the Model</title>
      <link>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://persdre.github.io/intermine-training-portal/python-tutorial/15/</guid>
      <description>This tutorial will help you utilise the module to get details about the data model of various mines. These are additional examples, besides the ones covered here Text Tutorial   Video Tutorial     You can see the script here
Try Live  You can try live here</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>